People like to believe
that their businesses have unique
problems, but they don't.
Over the last year,
I've actually worked with close to 2,000
businesses, and almost
every single business
is making the same mistake.
And here's the elephant in the room.
I come from a fitness background.
I like to use fitness analogies,
but only about 65% of the people I work
with are fitness businesses.
And the next 12 points of advice I'm going
to give you
would work fine with a fitness business,
but they will also work in every other
niche that I work with.
So let's start with content.
Too many people try to make their content
about themselves, and they fail to
realize that every single person on the
internet doesn't really care about you.
And the quicker you can come to terms with
that, the easier you can move on with
it. They care about themselves.
I even think the people that love charity
and donating money
are even only being philanthropic because
it makes
them feel good. Human beings
are very self-centered.
So fitness analogy, this
is how I lost five kilograms in
four weeks,
could very easily be how you could lose
five kilograms of
fat in four weeks.
The story's still the same.
The anecdote's still the same.
But you made it about them, not you.
Outside of fitness,
how I edit YouTube videos to
make them look like they're Hollywood
grade.
How you can edit your videos to make it
look like you've worked in Hollywood for
years. Same information, same delivery,
pretty much same everything, just change
the packaging.
If you just twist your words to make it
about them, they're probably
going to listen a lot more, and
if you keep delivering content
that helps that
person with their problems,
eventually they're going to go,
"This person's a
legend," only because you helped them.
Even this video, this isn't about me.
It's about me helping you. And
if you watch enough of these,
you'll probably go,
"Do you know what?
I like this guy." It's a bit like
when people let you talk about
yourself a lot.
Human beings love to talk about
themselves.
If you go for a beer with someone
and they just keep asking you questions
and you
talk for 90% of the time, you'll leave
and go, "What a great conversation that
was." The second blatantly obvious thing
that people still fail to do with their
content, they don't problem solve. We
are in the business of solving problems.
Your problems are, there
are just various bottlenecks through your
business that
maybe you've identified
and maybe you haven't.
And when I say a bottleneck
is there's a flow of people
and interest through your
business,
then it just stops at some point.
And it might be at content,
or it might be in the stage we're about to
go into.
So again, fitness analogy.
Someone posts their workout.
Cool bro, nice one. Great
that you started Hyrox.
Which to me just says
that you're a shit runner
and a shit lifter.
No problem solved. Whereas if you
were to take one component of that
workout, then find the one problem
that people have with that component,
and then
to turn that problem into a hook,
let's say, and I'm making this up,
I riff these
videos. Let's say one of the components
is a back squat.
Something I do and struggle with in a back
squat is where my eye line is.
So I get a bit of chalk,
and I draw a little X on the wall in a
good position for
the eye line, so as I sit into the squat,
I have something to look at. Just helps.
So rather than me going, "Hey,
here's my workout of the day."
If you're someone
that struggles to keep your eyes up
when doing a back squat,
maybe get this bit of
chalk and do this. Bit of Inquisit,
whatever. Cool.
Outside of fitness,
let's say someone's using Photoshop to
create thumbnails.
They have plenty of problems.
Maybe integrating AI.
Maybe how they structure
and prioritize the hierarchy of the
importance of that
thing there.
You could then say to someone, "Hey,
if you're struggling with
thumbnail design,
let's look into the hierarchy of the
importance when we're making
different types of thumbnails." The
content shouldn't be,
I made 10 thumbnails.
The content should be, you have a problem,
I have the solution. Let me show you.
Then the third problem
that everyone's making in content
is probably not putting
enough importance into the first three
seconds of content.
Maybe in long form like this,
we could say the first 15 seconds.
And if I'm completely honest,
the only part of this video
that I script is
the first 10 seconds,
because it's the most important.
It's where you're going to click
and determine whether
or not the value that I'm
going to give in this video
is appropriate to the issues
that you face.
So you'll note there's just one paragraph
there, and the rest are bullet points.
People put so much effort into the later
stages of a video, but people have already
gone. Even the middle part of the video.
Even if you use props, analogies, setups,
payoffs.
You might even get dressed up
and get in the shower
and cry to get dramatic effect.
If you don't retain people to the middle,
it doesn't matter. They're not there.
Same towards the end of the video.
The first five seconds, arguably,
if you're
going to spend 30 minutes making a video,
spend 15 to 20 minutes
doing the first 10 seconds. Scene changes,
dramatization.
The more effort you put into the early
sta-- A bit like this, like a
relationship. Just came to me.
When you first start dating someone,
those first
three dates are crucial. By month three
or four, you're ripping a fart, it's
fine.
Make sure in the early stages you do the
most effort and
interest because if you don't get
that right,
there is no latter stage to worry or
care about. So park that from content.
Let's move into data.
And data sounds boring, I know.
In essence, over the last few years,
I've noticed
that assets don't work like they used to.
Hey, here's a free guide. No one cares.
Here's an e-book. No one cares.
I write and sell books for a living.
I'm a three times number one bestselling
author, flex.
Even then,
I struggle to get people to buy a book,
and I spend a year writing it
and sell it for a tenner,
and still they don't want it.
So when you scratch together an e-book in
an afternoon, it's no wonder people don't
want it.
I'm seeing a trend of people wanting
bite-sized chunks of information.
If you've got an e-book that's 30 pages,
take each page, make it a well-curated
email that you could send on a daily
basis.
Then rather than giving someone too much
that they never come back and read, you
hit them with little jabs
and you break them down. Boom.
How many fights are won not with knockout
punches, but the accumulation of
lots of medium impact punches
that just break people down to the point
they give
up? Death by a thousand paper cuts.
That's how our approach should be.
Don't take these massive assets
that you wouldn't read.
If I sent you a transcript of my latest
book and asked for a blurb, you would
scroll through it and you'd go, "Yeah,
it was nice, mate. Yeah, good. Great book.
Thanks." People now have attention deficit
disorder worse than ever before.
Cheers, TikTok.
So let's prioritize making sure
that we can break it down into the
most bite-sized chunks of information
possible that people will actually finish.
Again, similar to content
that we spoke about before,
someone finishing the
thing we are putting out
is more important than giving it all to
them at one point.
Next point I'll talk about,
as a gold standard, I like to feel
and set for my
clients that 20% of your total following
should be on your email list.
100,000 followers should be 40,000 people
on your email list.
If that is less than 20%,
you need to stop what you're doing from
the content
creation standpoint
and start prioritizing growing the email
list. 20%.
And your focus on a daily basis should be,
where am I at?
Do I make content to grow my following
and engagement and reach, or do I do
whatever I can to harvest my existing
database of content followers
for more email addresses?
Too many people are too worried about
growing The
wider reach without looking into the most
crucial component of aiming for
20% of total following on their email
list.
So take a look at where you're at, and
if you do need to grow your email
database,
you should consider working with me.
There'll be links in the description,
but relax, mate, all right?
I'm here to help you,
not for your business.
And out of the thousands of businesses
I've worked with,
people seem to worry about
open rates on their emails. Look,
in the world we live in,
we all log on first
thing in the morning, click, click, click,
click, click, mark as read.
We just want them out our inbox,
but we don't want to delete them because
we'd want
to be able to reference back to them.
That will send to the email provider
that I read it when I didn't.
A bit like Chris Williamson. Yeah, mate,
I'm on your email list.
You're my business partner.
We've got a great business together,
but I've been
marking them as unread for quite a long
time. I'm sorry, brother.
Instead,
worry about email list as size of total
following
and clicks through to landing page.
How many people are clicking
and visiting the landing page?
That's really the metric we care about.
And then the next part of
that will be landing pages,
how many visits to how many
sales. And again, some people go, "Oh,
there must be something wrong with my
landing page," but they only sent 45
people there.
Which I suppose brings us into the next
part of this video, the importance of
landing pages and sales pages.
There will be a certain amount of people
that visit
that page to pop out one client.
And over time,
we're going to increase that.
Again, I use this analogy a lot.
I used to work in door-to-door sales for
Npower.
I'd knock on 100 doors, I'd get one sale.
But in the early stages,
I'd have to knock on 200 doors to make a
sale.
And if I hadn't quit because of those cold
November mornings in GL1, and the fact I
always secretly thought deep down as a
21-year-old, one day I might just get
invited in by some MILF. Never happened.
All I got was a cup of tea from an old
lady who had a dog with one eye.
Where were we? If I'd continued in
that realm of door-to-door sales,
maybe I'd get
that to one in 80, one in 70.
It would only have got better with time,
very rarely
worse. So instead, just try
and find out the average amount of people
you need to
send to a landing page to get a client.
And then over time, make tweaks
and changes like A/B split testing landing
pages, a
short one, a long one,
one that's video heavy,
one that's text heavy, one that
uses light colors, dark text, and one
that uses dark background, light text.
And trust me, dark mode is a way
that we're all going.
Even over the last two months,
every time I critique people's landing
pages, I'm
like, "Hey, bro,
show me this in dark mode.
Let's get rid of that white background.
Let's get some white text." Because even
that's what I get in Discord, but that
could be because I'm on dark mode for
everything, but I don't know.
Even now when I'm writing documents,
I've just rewritten the whole entire
mentorship,
and I had to do it on dark mode. P.S.
The reason I've rewritten the whole
mentorship is a lot of you seem to think
incorrectly that I only work with fitness
businesses.
So I've actually redone the whole thing,
which is why I was offline for a month,
and removed all examples that
were fitness-based.
So whether you've got a car garage,
whether you're a consultant,
whether you're a
lawyer,
the business mentorship fits those needs.
So we should use the VSL.
We should use the landing page as a place
we send people, clients pop out.
The way we do that
is to have a very good VSL,
a video sales letter, a video that
represents your business,
brings over a bit of personality,
shows what you're like.
You can talk through objections.
Remember in "8 Mile" Eminem,
when it gets to the
end,
he kind of tells them all of the things
that's bad about, "Yeah, I do live in
a trailer park with my mom." All of those
things.
He actually gets in their head,
so by the time they get to the end of the
rap, they
know everything.
That's what your VSL should do.
It should leave them at the end,
where even if you've disclosed all the
points of
weakness and everything else
that you have with whatever it
is you're selling, they
can still make an informed decision
whether or not to partake in business with
you.
These landing pages must look clean.
They must look professional.
Again, like the first date,
you wouldn't wear dirty shoes to a first
date.
If you had a job interview,
you're doing the tie up,
you're actually going to do
your top button up for the first time.
That's what this is.
For many people, this
is where they're going to determine
whether they do business
with you or not.
And too many people think they can skimp
and use Squarespace or
host the landing page on AWeber
or on MailChimp.
And to be honest, it looks rubbish.
And people go, "Oh, but Leadpages
is $49 a month." Look, compared to what it
costs to have a member of staff that
were to do this for you,
it's not expensive.
It's a business expense
that you can write off.
It's a legitimate one.
And Leadpages works night
and day to choose fonts.
So many people get their fonts wrong.
Serif, sans serif, too small.
Sometimes just increasing the size of your
font can get you more business.
And you can A/B split test that
if you don't believe me.
Too much text, they're gone.
Too many videos.
I critiqued a landing page the other day
that had eight videos.
Seven of them were testimonials. I
was like, "Brother,
if these testimonials are so
good and of so much value,
why didn't you just take the best parts of
them and put
them into your main VSL video?" Then you
could have taken them on a journey, and
when you get to the point in the flow,
which I teach about getting them to why
they
should believe you, you could say, "And
if you don't believe me, here's Trevor."
Boom. Take the best part of
that testimonial, bring it to the front,
intertwine it
in the story arc of your VSL.
And ultimately,
we're trying to make people decide
whether or not they want to do business
with us.
And the sales process can be automated.
You ever been to a restaurant where at the
front they just have a menu in a little
glass cabinet, no one at front of house,
just a menu. Low pressure.
Because when there's someone stood next to
the menu, people go, "Oh, I don't want
to be sold into it.
I don't want to be pressured." But
if you just leave the menu
there for you to go peruse, you go over,
you go, "They do paella." And your aunt
goes, "Paella." And you're like, "Oh,
we're not going here.
Not putting up with this for fucking 10
minutes." Whereas the person that's there
with the menu you can feel
is a bit daunting, which
is why I don't really like
sales calls because you feel very
pressured.
You feel like you're wasting people's
times.
Just go over, peruse, and you go,
"Do you know what?
This is the perfect price point.
Looks busy,
but it looks like there's a table for
us.
This is the place for me." You qualify
yourself in or qualify yourself out.
I think that the qualification process of
being right or not should be automated.
It should be something people make on
their own.
And even if they can't afford you,
maybe they can in the future.
Or their situation gets worse,
and they then deem the value of what
you're selling
being more important.
Other things I come across,
and I work with a lot of people
that are too expensive.
And everyone in the business guru world
saying the other
way, "Charge more, premium pricing,
high ticket." I'm like, "Yeah, bro, cool.
You've got four clients." I don't want to
give people the business class
service with the economy prices. Mate,
you ain't got the luxury, brother.
Your airplane is empty.
Bring those prices down.
You may be a great coach,
but I also need you busy.
I need you working with people so you know
them.
Similarly,
I've just spent a year working with 2,000
people so I can come on here
and rift about all these problems.
Me being busy is the biggest blessing
ever.
Because although I could've charged five
times as much and worked with five times
less people,
which would've been nice probably for my
hairline and the level of
stress I have,
I love getting to know people's problems
through all different
various and niches, whatever.
Being busy is a superpower.
Because you wake me up at 4:00 a.m.
in the morning,
pouring a bucket of ice water
on me, I can get up
and talk to you about all the problems
people are facing in
2025 because I'm living and breathing it.
Although I would've been awake because my
son is in a sleep regression phase
through teething, but that's fine.
It's fine. It's fine.
Being busy is so much better than being
expensive. If you can be both, amazing.
That's what we're working towards,
but we need that golden elixir of demand.
You want to make sure you've got enough
people on your books that if a few drop
out, you can replace them, and
that you're in the trenches understanding
people's
problems.
Because if you're working with more
clients, you're getting more problems
in front of you,
which give you great ideas for content,
whether it's YouTube,
Instagram, TikTok, Facebook,
YouTube Shorts, whatever it is.
Content, data, landing pages,
sales process,
and automating it makes it way
better. Just briefly,
if you do sales calls, people book in,
they see
that your times are all open, they bounce.
Or you're busy, they bounce.
You're on different time zone,
they bounce.
They don't show up, that annoys you.
They don't buy, that annoys you.
And you don't want to be deflated with the
efforts of your business.
And if people... This
is the best thing for me, right?
From a mental health perspective,
nine out of 10 people could visit,
or do you know
what?
99 out of 100 people could leave my
landing page and go, "Fuck this.
I'm out." I don't know about it.
All I know is the people
that come in through the
door, and I'm thinking,
"What a great business I run.
I'm getting five new clients today."
If I jump on a sales call and I'm spending
hours in front of people
and they're going, "Yeah, yeah, yeah,
sounds great, James,
but no, thanks." Ugh. I get depressed. No,
I'm joking.
Long and short of the story,
if you can work on those,
you can do amazing.
Now, I want you to work with me.
I'm good at this stuff.
And yeah, my mentorship's not cheap,
but think about this.
How many clients do you need to win to pay
back what I charge you?
At the moment, it's what?
2,000 US dollars.
For the majority of you looking at five
clients over a few months.
It's a business expense.
I'm good at what I do.
After this video,
I'm sending it to Declan to get edited.
I'm getting in the Discord.
I'm there for the next four hours.
It's Sunday.
I don't have weekends.
I don't have holidays. I'm in here.
I'm in the trenches.
Because you should be too.
That's why you're watching this video.
There's a level of obsession required to
do well in this industry, and I'm as
obsessed as they come.
If you want to join me
and get on my level, there's a link
in the description. If not,
there's 30 ways in 30 days I can help your
business for
free.
And if you're one of those people that's
never going to buy from me and just
enjoy the videos, well,
I'll see you the next time I upload one.
Have a fucking good weekend.
If you made it this far
and you're not determined to
buy my shit, well,
YouTube recommends this video here,
and YouTube is a very smart
bugger, so I recommend you watch that.
Bye-bye.